# TOYIN S BADMOS

07411791699· toyin.badmos@yahoo.com .LinkedIn.com/in/toyin-b-45461759 Kennington, SE11 4PJ, London

# SCRUM MASTER/DELIVERY MANAGER

Experienced Scrum Master and Delivery Manager with a proven history of understanding teams, facilitating difficult discussions, and building complex systems. Demonstrated ability to foster an environment of collaboration and productivity while driving adherence to agile philosophy. Track record of applying project management best practices, curating technical expertise, and business acumen to consistently achieve targeted results. Excel at guiding agile principles and facilitation skills to ensure teams were working in An agile mindset and utilizing Scrum and other frameworks. Highly effective communicator with the ability to forge exceptional relationships with teams, C-level executives, and other key stakeholders.

#### **KEY COMPETENCIES**

Stakeholder Engagement Coaching Mentoring Facilitation Change Management Kanban Scrumban Scrum DevOps Project/Product Management Jira & Trello Scrum Ceremonies Life Cycle Management Lean Practices Planning Management

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# www.solutionfocusedworld.com Scrum Master/Agile Practitioner

Jul 2022 - Present

Commissioned the implementation of Agile mindset in a dynamic environment while using its frameworks to manage workloads, solve social issues and improve actions transparency while abiding by local legislations. Drove the understanding by creation of Agile Centre of Excellence and tirelessly improving impediments while dealing with dependencies iteratively.

#### Accomplishments:

- Commissioning the implementation of an Agile mindset in a dynamic environment while using its frameworks to manage workloads, solve social issues, and improve actions transparency by 30%
- Drove the understanding by creating of Agile Centre of Excellence and tirelessly improving impediments while dealing with dependencies iteratively
- Introduction of an organization-wide process to seamlessly manage work streams leading to a 40% increase in visibility
- Coach colleagues through workshops leading to the streamlined application of frameworks
- Mentoring and maintenance of teams in the application of Safe Place leading to reduction of anti-patterns by 35%
- · Establishment and maintenance of teams along the line of functions
- Improvement of reporting procedures by deriving team-relative metrics

#### Collabera (Tata & BT)

Mar 2022 - Jun 2022

## Release Train Engineer/ Delivery Manager/ Scrum Master

Assisted two cross-functional teams of developers and product owners using Agile processes while steadily generating increments to boost business ROI. Determined and managed tasks, issues, risks, and action items. Used agile philosophy values, principles, and practices to plan, support and deliver solutions. Scheduled and facilitated scrum events, meetings, and decision-making processes. Coordinated teams in ascertaining product requirements. Track timelines while managing cadences to improve business agility.

#### **Accomplishments:**

- Played a pivotal role in initiating the monitoring of metrics in Jira leading to a 40% visibility increase.
- Coached squads in agile ways of working, leading to a 20% decrease in teams' wide silos.
- Leveraged skills in providing support to C-suite stakeholders in the drive to bridge the communication gap with development squads
- · Created increments every sprint leading to a 15% increase in delivery
- Led initiatives to boost departmental agility and contributed to overall departmental ROI.

# Pracctic Ltd April 2020 - Feb 2022

#### **Senior Scrum Master**

Worked as Agile coach and mentored two cross-functional, distributed teams on the adoption of scrum and other agile frameworks. Facilitated daily stand-up meetings, and ensured that all team members are aware of their current status and any roadblocks they may face. Ensured that scrum teams adhered to scrum values and principles at all times during the project. Assisted with planning and executing sprints, facilitated backlog grooming sessions, assisted in estimating work effort for user stories/tasks, etc. Provided support for continuous improvement within the organization by facilitating retrospective meetings after each project or iteration. Developed relationships across multiple business units to ensure cross-functional collaboration on projects as needed. Served product owners, and developers across teams in the quest to meet sprint goals. Monitored, escalated, and recorded software bugs and issues with system vendors Trained teams in using Agile tools such as Jira and Trello.

#### **Accomplishments:**

- · Assisted teammates with sharing information and training, resulting in a 10% increase in delivery output.
- · Contributed to the development of new team topography, which increased intra-team involvement by 20%.
- Promoted team-building exercises to improve relationships within the team.
- Assisted teams in adopting agile attitudes and boosting their velocity by 15% in the first three months.
- Imparted training to internal and external stakeholders on how to interact with agile teams.
- Coached teams on story mapping, user story writing, acceptance criteria, and meeting the INVEST criteria.

#### IBK Innovation (formerly IBK Engineering)

April 2016 - Mar 2020

#### **Scrum Master**

Led and mentored two teams in using agile philosophy and scrum practices. Scheduled scrum of scrums events with other scrum masters for scrum teams. Developed strategies to deal with anti-patterns after observing them. Aided product owner with the backlog and ensured it was properly prioritized according to business value. Worked in teams to identify dependencies and developed solutions to reduce them. Organized and led sprint reviews while ensuring that the lessons are put into practice.

#### Accomplishments:

- Supported complete Kanban deployment as a delivery framework, leading to increased stakeholder management engagement by 60%.
- Successfully revamped business process that resulted in a 10% boost in ROI, supported by the product owner and PMO office.
- Facilitated the introduction of relative measurements, which resulted in a 15% increase in monitoring.
- Tracked metrics using Jira, then reported a leading 20% increase in process visibility.
- Established T-depth by encouraging teammates into mentoring or "passing on" uncommon team knowledge to other colleagues.

#### **EDUCATION**

SAFe - Scaled Agile Scrum Master 5.1 (2021-2023)

www.scrum.org (PSMI 2021)

BA Linguistics with Spanish (2012-2016) Birkbeck University of London